Diego Grados Bedoya

I am a quality-driven bioscience engineer and applied statistician using interdisciplinary approaches to address sustainable development challenges focused on soil-crop-environment interactions, agroecosystems analysis, and resource use efficiency. I have experience working on international research projects with diverse partners in a multidisciplinary context (Belgium, Colombia, Cuba, and Peru). My ability to work on different problems is supported by my analytical, technical, and communication skills. Throughout my career, I have also cultivated my enthusiasm for the creation of integrated solutions, focusing on the data analysis, modeling, and visualization.

Personal Data

Address: 30/0102 Verbindingslaan, Leuven, Belgium

Phone: (+32) 485 02 20 07

Email: diegogradosb@gmail.com

Web: https://diegogradosb.github.io/

Relevant Experience

JAN 2020 -Mar 2020 Postdoctoral Researcher - KU LEUVEN, Leuven - Belgium

Divison of MeBioS - Biosystems Department - Faculty of Bioscience Engineering

- Dissemination of research results in seminars, workshops, and peer-reviewed journals.

Reference: Prof. Dr. Eddie Schrevens

APR 2016 -DEC 2019 PhD Researcher - KU LEUVEN, Leuven - Belgium

Divison of MeBioS - Biosystems Department - Faculty of Bioscience Engineering

- Developing of multi-target and system modeling methodologies for the agroecosystems' sustainability assessment.
- Dissemination of results in seminars, workshops, peer-reviewed journals, and international conferences.
- Mentoring and supervision of BSc and MSc thesis students in Peru (UNALM and UNCP) and Belgium (KU Leuven).

Reference: Prof. Dr. Eddie Schrevens

Nov 2014 -Apr 2019 **Research Assistant** - *VLIR/UOS-UNALM PROJECT*, Lima - Peru *Strengthening of Smallholder Horticultural Systems Subproject*

- Co-leading the study of soil-crop-environment interactions in the Peruvian Costal Desert.
- Installation of soil, meteorological, and irrigation equipment.
- Design and installation of agricultural experiments under drip irrigation systems.

References: Prof. Dr. Eddie Schrevens, Prof. Dr. Guido Wyseure, Prof. Dr. Jan Diels

SEP 2013 -DEC 2018 **Research Officer** - *VLIR/UOS-UNALM PROJECT*, Junin - Peru Sustainable Agriculture in the Central Peruvian Andes Subproject

- Leading the design and installation of agricultural experiments under rainfed conditions.
- Implementation of rational databases, development of soil-crop models and advanced statistical techniques.
- Analysis and evaluation of agroecosystems using participatory approaches.

References: Prof. Dr. Eddie Schrevens, Prof. Dr. Sady García

FEB 2013 -APR 2019 Research Officer - VLIR/UOS-UNALM PROJECT, Junin | Lima - Peru

Drone Technology in Agriculture Subproject

- Leading the feasibility study for uses of drone technology in agroecosystems.
- In charge of drone flights in Peruvian's Andes and Arid regions and the implementation of GIS databases.
- Development of mathematical and statistical techniques for land use classification and field experiments.

References: Prof. Dr. Eddie Schrevens, MSc. Dries Raymaekers

JAN 2012 -DEC 2018 Research Officer - VLIR/UOS-UNALM PROJECT, Junin - Peru

Watersheds Management Subproject

- Leading the study of soil-crop-environment interactions and hydrology in the Peruvian Central Andes.
- Installation of soil, climatological, and hydrometric equipment.
- Implementation of databases, application of hydrological models, and assessment of rainfall-runoff relations.

References: Prof. Dr. Eduardo Chávarri, Prof. Dr. Guido Wyseure

Education

APR 2016 - **PhD in Bioscience Engineering**, *Mechatronics*, *Biostatistics and Sensors* - KU Leuven, Belgium Thesis Title: "Multi-target methodologies for the improvement of agricultural systems research

- Study cases at system and field level". | Advisor: Prof. Dr. Eddie Schrevens

JAN 2007 - **BSc in Agricultural Engineering**, *Water Resources* - Agrarian National University La Molina, Peru DEC 2011 Honor Thesis Title: "Analysis of flood peaks in small Andean watersheds, Junin Department,

Peru (2011-2012 Period)". | Advisor: Prof. Dr. Eduardo Chávarri

Publications

- 1. **Grados, D.,** García, S., Schrevens, E., 2020. Assessing the potato yield gap in the Peruvian Central Andes. *Journal of Agricultural Systems*, 181, 102817. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.agsy.2020.102817.
- 2. **Grados, D.,** Reynafarje, X., Schrevens, E., 2020. A methodological approach to assess canopy NDVI–based tomato dynamics under irrigation treatments. *Journal of Agricultural Water Management*.[IN PRESS].
- 3. **Grados, D.,** Schrevens, E., 2019. Multidimensional analysis of environmental impacts from potato agricultural production in the Peruvian Central Andes. *Science of The Total Environment*, 663, 927–934. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2019.01.414.
- 4. **Grados, D.,** Schrevens, E., 2019. Cassava NDVI analysis: A nonlinear mixed model approach based on UAV-imagery. *Journal of Photogrammetry, Remote Sensing and Geoinformation Science*. [UNDER REVIEW].

Conference Proceedings [PEER-REVIEWED]

- Schrevens, E., Heuts, R., Reynafarje, X., **Grados, D.**, Diels, J., Potential strategies to reduce nitrogen emissions to the environment in an intensive cauliflower-leek rotation system: A modelling approach. In: Acta Horticulturae (1253) (269–278). International Symposium on Water and Nutrient Relations and Management of Horticultural Crops, Istanbul, Turkey, 12-16 Aug 2018. http://dx.doi.org/10.17660/actahortic.2019.1253.36.
- Grados, D., García, S., Schrevens, E., Nitrogen and water use efficiency under rain-fed potato agriculture: An experimental study. In: *Acta Horticulturae* (1253) (243–252). *International Symposium on Water and Nutrient Relations and Management of Horticultural Crops*, Istanbul, Turkey, 12-16 Aug 2018. http://dx.doi.org/10.17660/actahortic.2019.1253.33.
- Grados, D., Vetters, E., Heuts, R., Schrevens, E., A model based technical sustainability analysis of potato production systems in the Mantaro Valley, Central Highlands, Peru. In: Acta Horticulturae (1154) (155-152). Symposium on Applications of Modelling as an Innovative Technology in the Horticultural Supply Chain, Wageningen, The Netherlands, 11-14 Oct 2015. http://dx.doi.org/10.17660/actahortic.2017.1154.20.
- Grados, D., Vera, J., Schrevens, E., Corn-faba bean associations in the Peruvian Central Andes. In: Acta Horticulturae (1128) (79-88). International Symposium on Horticulture in Developing Countries and World Food Production, Brisbane, Australia, 19-22 Aug 2014. http://dx.doi.org/10.17660/actahortic. 2016.1128.11.

Teaching Experience

- FA 2017 Applied Multivariate Statistical Analysis Master in Bioscience Engineering, KU Leuven
 - 2019 **Graduate Teacher Assistant**: Data visualization and manipulation, matrix algebra, R programming. Diverse multivariate techniques: ordination, cluster analysis, and discrimination.

Professor: Dr. Eddie Schrevens

FA 2019 Biological Production Systems - Bachelor in Bioscience Engineering, KU Leuven

Undergraduate Teacher Assistant: Review sessions to assess soil-crop-environment interactions of diverse agroecosystems. Mathematical modelling of agroecosystems.

Professor-Coordinator: Dr. Eddie Schrevens

SP 2016 Ecosystems Modelling - Master in Bioscience Engineering, KU Leuven

Graduate Teacher Assistant: Introductory statistical concepts, data visualization and manipulation,

R programming. Mathematical modelling of agroecosystems.

Professors: Dr. Eddie Schrevens, Dr. Herman RAMON

Fellowships

2020 **FONDECYT-CONCYTEC** Research Grant (5 500€)

2016 - 2019 VLIR/UOS-UNALM PhD Fellowship (82 000€)

2013 | 2014 | 2015 VLIR/UOS-UNALM International Scholar Fellowships (67 000€)

Languages

English: Full Professional Proficiency Italian: Elementary Working Proficiency

French: Limited Working Proficiency Spanish: Native/Bilingual

Technical Skills

Programming R, MATLAB, Python, FORTRAN

Markup Markdown, LATEX

OS Microsoft Windows, Linux

Other HYDRUS, DSSAT, RStudio, SAS, Office, HPC, QGIS, GRASS GIS, Git, GitHub